{"id":"2018_16","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"For with you is the fountain of life; in your light we see light.\" â€“ Psalm 36:9","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_16_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_16_2","questionText":"2. From the past week's study, what made the most significant impact to you in the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 2 Samuel 1.\nDavid grieved Saul's and Jonathan's deaths.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"1:1-999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_16_3","questionText":"3. How did the man's report of Saul's death compare with the actual events? Why might he have changed the story? (See 1 Samuel 31:1-7.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"31:1-7"}]},{"id":"2018_16_4","questionText":"4. Why was David unwilling to celebrate Saul's death? What does that say about David's relationship with and beliefs about God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_16_5","questionText":"5. What does David's response to the news reveal about him? Which qualities will you ask God to grow in you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 2 Samuel 2:1-3:5.\nDavid's and Saul's men battled over who would be Israel's next king.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"2:1-3:5"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_16_6","questionText":"6. What decision did David face? How did David decide what to do next? (See 1 Samuel 16:12-13 and 2 Samuel 2:1-3.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"16:12-13"},{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"2:1-3"}]},{"id":"2018_16_7","questionText":"7. Did Abner's actions make the situation better or worse between David's and Saul's men? Why?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_16_8","questionText":"8. What reminders, warnings or examples do you see in this passage? How could you apply them to your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 2 Samuel 3:6-29.\nAbner shifted his loyalty to David and was killed.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"3:6-29"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_16_9","questionText":"9. What prompted Abner's change in loyalty? How did Abner demonstrate his loyalty to David?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_16_10","questionText":"10. What do you learn from the differences in how David and Joab responded to Abner? How do you respond to those who have hurt or harmed you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_16_11","questionText":"11. How do you see God working to establish David as king, in the good and hard times?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 2 Samuel 4:1-12.\nDavid ordered the execution of Ish-Bosheth's murderers.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"4:1-12"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_16_12","questionText":"12. What were Saul's men hoping to gain by killing Ish-Bosheth? What were the consequences?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_16_13","questionText":"13. How do you see people engaging in self-promotion today? Which are most tempting to you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_16_14","questionText":"14. What do you learn about choices and consequences from this passage?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 2 Samuel 1-4.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"1:1-4:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_16_15","questionText":"15. Through this week's lesson, how is God challenging your view of the purpose of struggles or to remain patient instead of taking matters into your own hands?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}